

Shubham Awasthi

Order To Cash

Contact

Address

Gurugram, India 122003

Phone

7838810133

E-mail

Awasthsh@Gmail.com

LinkedIn

https://www.linkedin.com/in/shubham-awasthi-409241

Technical Profile

- Microsoft Powerpoint
- Microsoft Excel
- Oracle
- Cerner
- SAP

Competencies

Problem solving

Team Building

Time management

Client management

Seeking a career in an organization where I can put my earnest endeavor in facing challenges and lead my team to triumph Where I can utilize my talent, experience, knowledge and skill in a position to purse challenges to turn any adverse situation into a favorable environment.

- An enthusiastic & high energy driven professional with an experience 2+ year in the area of Healthcare with R1 RCM.
- Strong technical and medical skills, excellent research and financial analysis abilities.
- To seek and maintain full-time position that offers professional challenges utilizing interpersonal skills, excellent time management and problem-solving skills.

Work History

2020-09 -Current

Senior Analyst

R1 RCM, Gurugram

I have been working as an Analyst in Financial Clearing Centre (FCC) in Healthcare Revenue Cycle Management with R1 RCM (IMH Healthcare), Gurgaon from September 2020.

- Verification of Coverage (SLA day 1-5), Claims
 Adjudication needs to update the eligibility date
 and benefits (deductible, out of pocket, Co pay,
 co insurance,) as per the plan/payer using the
 provided payers websites or by calling on
 providers line,
- FCC applies the principles of strong people, excellent processes, and effective technology to provide excellent customer service and better patient outcomes,
- Results-focused to ensure consistent team performance within SLA,
- Updating the DRG, DX, CPT, HCPCS codes in the R1RCM tools using the provided providers websites and tools,
- Maintain the patients accounts that includes inpatient, outpatient, observations stay and surgery patients, of the facility Providence hospital,
- Communication with support Team and implement the organization's operation policies,
- Working in multiple buckets to process the accounts to achieve the daily, weekly and

Analytics program experience

Knowledge of business operations

monthly targets,

- Working of service and Authorization, Service Entry, Pre-Reg and shelling (Live Process),
- Work on Different R1 Websites Like UHC, Humana, Medicaid, Availity, Cigna, Noridian, Select Health ,BCBS AL, OOS, Humana, UMR, OPTUM, Medicaid, Aetna etc,
- Complete the Coverage, benefits and Authorization and update the facility host and R1RCM hub,
- Providing Trainings to New hire Employees in process,
- High quality delivery is required that is 98%,
- High targets are required to be achieved,

2018-08 -2020-02

Business Associate

IBM, Gurugram

- I have worked in medical billing where we have to bill hospital claims to insurance for Medicare Part D drug coverages. An Express Scripts Holding Company is a pharmacy benefit management (PBM)
- organization. The company processes
 pharmaceuticals claim for US citizens through a
 network of retails pharmacies. We dispense
 medications for chronic long-term diseases, such
 as diabetes, cancer, or heart disease, directly to
 members by home delivery.
- Worked on tool named as PEGA and RX HOME.
- Process invoices as per client requirements.
- I update all the boxes in claim form. We work on Hospital billing.
- We bill inpatient and outpatient both claims.
- I was working in a pilot queue batch for high dollar billing claims.
- Create Medical record number (MRN) which is very important to raise claim.
- Providing Supportive documentations for Audits.
- Preparing Daily, Weekly and Monthly Accounts
 Receivable reports for receivable accounts asper
 defined SLA by client.
- Manage Sales order management Queue for life saving drugs.
- Apply the payment against of open invoices and Identify the unapplied invoices.

- Managing SOP's (Standard Operating Procedure) of all process activity
- Engaged with customers to build business relationships.
- Developed and updated policies and procedures, maintaining compliance with statutory, regulatory and local, state and federal guidelines relating to HIPAA, benefits administration and
- general liability.

2017-06 -2017-07

Internship

PANASONIC INDIA, Gurugram

Completed a project on Order to Cash Process

- Order Processing
- Invoicing Processing
- Good and Service Tax (GST)
- Sales Order Processing in S.A.P
- Maintaining the Calendar of the Company
- Creating the invoices as per the Purchase Order/ Sales Order

Education

2016-07 -2018-08 **MBA: Finance And Marketing**

GURU GOBIND SINGH INDRAPRASTHA UNIVERSITY -DELHI

2012-06 -2015-07 **BBA: Banking And Insurance**

GURU GOBIND SINGH INDRAPRASTHA UNIVERSITY -DELHI

Achievements

- Acquired pilot process training and knowledge from client, assisted in deciding SLA's, TAT, quality parameters for the new hires.
- Received client appreciation for having good product knowledge.
- Mentoring and training for the New Hire Training (NHT) batches